JHH - Computex Keynote - 6.1.26
________________
[INTRO VIDEO]
This is how intelligence is
made. A new kind of factory. Generator
of tokens. The building blocks of AI.
Tokens open a new frontier, turning data
into knowledge, reason, action. They
reveal patterns in complexity you could never
see. They guard our cities to keep us safe,
and lift us high above them. Tokens help
robots learn from us, work alongside us —
we go where they cannot. Closing the gap between
hurt and healing, so they’ll breathe easier. And
the smallest hearts beat stronger. Tokens are
helping us break new frontiers never attempted,
so we can reach our goal. To infinity… and
beyond… Together. Take the next great leap
into a bright future for all mankind. And
here, in Taipei, is where it all begins.
________________
[JANINE]
Welcome to the stage, NVIDIA founder and CEO,
Jensen Huang.
________________
[JENSEN]
Welcome to GTC,
Taiwan. So great to see all of you. Very good to
be home. I brought my parents home. Where are my
parents? Everybody give a round of applause
to my mom and dad. And a round of applause
for our pre-game show superstars, ladies
and gentlemen. Look how adorable they are.
The superstars of Taiwan.
There are so many of you here today. We
are broadcasting this right now to 70 other launch
parties across Taiwan. 70 different conferences
are going at the same time. Everybody is watching
this live. We have so much to tell you, and I
have so many partners to thank. It is incredible
how large our ecosystem in Taiwan has become.
Most of the time, when people think about
ecosystem, they think about our software stack.
They think about the developer ecosystem above
the computing systems that NVIDIA builds. But
NVIDIA’s ecosystem spans all the way upstream
to all of our supply chain here in Taiwan,
where it all begins, and downstream all the way
to data centers, and eventually to end users.
Today we’re going to talk about almost all of
the ecosystem. There are so many people to thank.
I love my ecosystem here. So many incredible
companies, some of my favorite ecosystem partners.
Taiwan’s rich ecosystem — the world’s best
supply chain ecosystem. Unbelievable.
Well, thank you all for being here. And
this year, our businesses together are
growing incredibly. In fact, somebody told me
last night that the annual GDP of Taiwan is
going to grow almost 10%. Unbelievable. Well,
we have a lot to talk about. Let’s get going.
Two years ago, when I was here, I started to talk
to you about how AI has moved from generative AI,
and other waves of AI that are coming.
The next wave of AI was agentic AI. And
today we can say that agentic AI has
arrived, that useful AI has arrived.
Now, what does this mean? This
is GitHub. This is, of course,
one of the first applications
of agentic AI — software coding.
One of the most valuable professions, an
incredibly large ecosystem — 30 million,
40 million professional software developers,
probably another couple hundred million who are
students and enthusiasts and so on and so forth.
But say 30, 40 million software developers in the
world code for a living. And this represents
most of them. This is GitHub. The pull request
is when they download software, they modify it,
and commit is when they push it back up. And so,
if you could look at this — in 2023 the
number of commits was 300 million, in 2024,
400 million, in 2025, 500 million commits. In the
first few months of 2026, it has nearly tripled.
Now what does that mean? 30 million software
developers representing about $3 trillion worth
of GDP — that is what they’re paid, $3 trillion
worth of salaries per year, which is generating
economic growth for the rest of the industries.
Say $100 trillion of the world’s industries is
impacted — generated by $3 trillion worth of
salary. That $3 trillion worth of salary is
now producing nearly three times as much output.
It’s effectively $9 trillion of productivity from
$3 trillion of salaries. Does that make any sense?
The difference is absolutely extraordinary. This
is the potential. This is the promise of AI.
The number of software engineers is actually
increasing. People talk about AI reducing
jobs — complete nonsense. It’s causing more
software engineers to be hired, and
the reason for that is very simple.
If you can hire a software engineer and you can
generate $9 trillion worth of productive work,
why wouldn’t you want to hire more software
engineers? If that line was flat, then obviously
people will hire fewer software engineers.
But because the output is so incredible,
people want to hire more software engineers. This
is going to show up in our economy very soon.
And so, the first thing is: useful AI has arrived.
Now, what does that mean from the industry’s
perspective? That means that tokens are now in
extraordinary demand. Because if you can do this,
you’re going to want to produce more of it. And
because tokens are now profitable units — tokens
are now profitable units of revenue. Because it is
now profitable, the AI companies want to build a
lot more tokens, generate a lot more tokens, build
more AI factories, which is the reason why compute
demand here in Taiwan has skyrocketed. It is
precisely the reason why all of you are so busy,
and your businesses are doing so well. In fact,
that looks like some of your stock prices.
The compute pattern has changed. Everything
has changed. So the first idea is that useful
AI has arrived. AI is now a profit generator.
AI is now a GDP generator. Behind it is a whole
new kind of computing pattern — not just a
large language model, but an agent. Today,
almost everything we’re going to talk
about is going to be based on this.
So let me take a quick moment and show you what
I’m talking about. This is an agent — an agent
application. In the old days, this would
be an application — this would be code,
and this would be an operating system.
Application, code running inside an application,
inside an operating system. Today, it is an agent,
which consists of a large language model, or many,
sitting inside a harness, and that harness
helps orchestrate it to do productive work.
This is the input — when that input comes,
it has to understand, observe, reason, act,
use tools. That tool could be a spreadsheet, a
web browser, a data processing engine, a database
engine, for example. This is orchestrated — this
harness orchestrates this routing of information.
Every single time it touches — either processing
the context, understanding what is happening,
reasoning about what to do, coming up with a plan
that it acts on — that orchestration is managed by
software. And so this is fundamentally an agent.
It deals with short-term memory — called working
memory — and long-term memory, just like we
do. And so the memory management system is
incredibly important. This entire system is called
an agent. The large language model is used to do
the thinking, and the harness connects everything
together, just like an operating system.
And so this is the new computing model.
This is what an agent can do — incredible
things. This is the big breakthrough:
the simultaneous convergence of large
language models that are now able to do
a really good job thinking, reasoning,
planning, using tools, and the fact that we
now have these harnesses that manage memory,
manage orchestration, use tools. We can now do
amazing things. Let me give you some examples.
This is a prompt. This is the code that is
generated, and this comes out. You guys — what
do you think? Pretty amazing, right? Look, we use
Claude Code here, but Codex does an incredible
job as well. Here’s another example. This is the
input: “Create a GIF — NVIDIA green dots on black,
scatter, form Taiwan 101 building, NVLink GTC
Taipei 2026, morph to NVIDIA logo, then scatter,
repeat.” Right? So you saw that — that was the
prompt. Here is the next one: “I lost my remote
control battery clip. It looks like this. Create
a CAD file.” It uses a tool, creates a CAD file,
ready for 3D printing to create a new one. Makes
sense? This is now the new computing pattern.
Whereas we used to launch an application, click
and type, we now replace that with explaining
to the AI what we want — our intent — and
the AI generates the code, or uses tools,
and produces the necessary output. This is
how computers are going to work in the future.
This is agentic AI. For two years we’ve been
building towards this, and now it has arrived.
Now, one of the big breakthroughs of course is
tool use. A lot of people have said, “Jensen,
agentic AI is coming, therefore all of the
software companies are going to go out of
business.” I said: it’s exactly the opposite.
Because there are going to be so many agents,
the world is no longer limited by the number
of people. Therefore, those agents are going
to use more tools than ever. This is actually
an incredible time to be a software company.
But the software has to be presented to the
agent in a way that the agent can use it.
This is a big breakthrough, and in fact, what
we have done — what NVIDIA’s treasure is — is
all of our CUDA libraries. I call them CUDA-X
libraries. This is NVIDIA’s treasure. Today,
we are able to now present these CUDA-X libraries
to agents who can use them much more effectively
than even humans. And so, this is a wonderful
time for CUDA-X libraries. Just take a look. 20
years ago we built CUDA, a single architecture for
accelerated computing. We reinvented computing.
A thousand CUDA-X libraries help developers
make breakthroughs in every field of science
and engineering. CUDA-X libraries are tools for
agents. cuLitho for computational lithography.
cuOpt for decision optimization. cuDSS for direct
sparse solvers. AI-Q for deep research across
structured and unstructured documents. Aerial for
AI RAN. PhysicsNeMo for differentiable physics.
Parabricks for genomics. At their foundation
are algorithms, and they are beautiful.
A round of applause for math — math is beautiful.
The computing pattern of software is going to
change. In fact, let’s come back to this. This
is the agent — the ultimate disaggregated and
distributed computing model. So many different
computers are going to be activated in order to
process this agent. The agent consists of model,
harness, tools, and skills, and a runtime. All
of that is running at different places in a data
center. You can think of the model as the brain,
the harness as the body, and the tools that
it uses, working in a runtime — think of it
as a workshop. So this is a person, a worker,
working with tools in a workshop. Of course,
this is being done at extraordinarily large
scales. And each one of those steps is running
in a different part of the computer.
You can see the large language model is
thinking — context processing, observing,
understanding the environment, reasoning,
coming up with a plan, and acting on the plan.
Every single time that happens, an entire rack
of Grace Blackwell NVLink 72 is activated.
It’s thinking with a large language model.
Whenever it uses a tool, a CPU is used. That tool
could be a C compiler. It could be Python. It
could be JavaScript. Or it could be accelerated
computing. Today’s agents are relatively simple
users of tools. Tomorrow, they’re going
to be very sophisticated users of tools,
which is the reason why the CUDA-X libraries
that I showed you are going to be incredibly
popular with agents. They solve some of the most
important problems the world knows. And all of
our CUDA-X libraries are now going to come with
skills that the AI could learn how to use. So the
CUDA-X library comes with skills — basically
a manual — the AI reads it and goes, “Aha,
that’s how you use it.” The ability to use these
libraries by agents is going to be incredible.
And so, the tools run on CPUs and GPUs and
large language models. The security harness
runs on CPUs and a security processor called the
DPU — NVIDIA’s BlueField. The orchestration of all
this runs on a CPU. This is the entire harness —
the CPUs orchestrating all of the work. One of the
hardest parts is memory. You can just imagine: the
working memory — called KV caching — is about what
to remember. Compression, not just compression,
but how to retrieve. Do you retrieve structured
data? Do you retrieve unstructured data? What is
the ontology, the relationship of all of these
different data structures to itself? That entire
processing is incredibly complicated. The memory
system of AI is going to cause the storage
system to be completely revolutionized.
As you can see, every aspect of this
computing model — this computing pattern,
this new application called an agent — is
fundamentally different than the way that
applications used to run: a whole bunch of
software sitting inside a binary, sitting
inside an operating system. This is the reason
— this disaggregated, this distributed, this
heterogeneous computing problem — is precisely the
reason we built our next generation: Vera Rubin.
Vera Rubin is not one chip. Vera Rubin
is not a GPU only. It starts with a GPU,
but Vera Rubin is incredible. This entire
thing is Vera Rubin. From end to end, it has
GPUs — Vera Rubin NVL72. It is orchestrated by
Vera CPUs that I’m going to tell you more about.
The storage systems — revolutionary. Vera, along
with ConnectX-9, our software stack called DOCA,
the security processor that’s inside so
that everything is encrypted at rest,
in motion, as well as in use. Everything
across this is secure because the AI model
is so precious. This is the reason why this
entire system observes confidential computing.
Each one of these systems would be a complete
revolution in itself. Vera Rubin is the most
ambitious endeavor in the history of our company.
The whole company worked on Vera Rubin — across
all 40,000 engineers, not to mention all of you.
All of you participated in the creation of this
entire system. Vera Rubin is really a miracle,
and it’s not just one chip — it is so many.
Well, it’s even beyond that. A long time ago,
NVIDIA used to be a GPU company. But over the
years we’ve evolved to become a systems company.
You’re looking here now at the most complex
system, the most complex ground-up system ever
designed. But ultimately, our customers and our
partners don’t want to buy computers. They want
to build AI factories, which is the reason why
NVIDIA has really started to transform ourselves
yet again. You can see so much of our technology
is now at the entire infrastructure scale. Our
partners are at infrastructure scale — power
generators, cooling systems, the grid providers.
So many industrial companies are now part of our
ecosystem, because ultimately we’re trying to
build an entire stack — just like GPUs, just
like when we were building Grace Blackwell NVLink
72, just like now, we are building a full-stack
system so that our customers could build
amazing AI infrastructure. Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
The world is racing to build AI factories
— the largest infrastructure buildout in
human history. AI factories are incredibly
complex. Every layer — chip, rack, network,
power, cooling, grid — must be designed together
from end to end, because compute is revenue.
NVIDIA DSX is the blueprint: a reference design
for building and operating AI factories at
maximum efficiency and profitability.
It starts with DSX Sim — the Omniverse
blueprint. Partners design and validate an
NVIDIA Vera Rubin AI factory before a single
rack is ordered. They plan the layout, simulate
the power and cooling, design the network,
validate every integration, test every change
in the digital twin. The factory powers on.
DSX OS takes over — it provisions, operates,
monitors, and remediates the infrastructure,
turning the installed systems into trusted,
multi-tenant, resilient, AI-ready capacity.
Today’s AI factories overprovision power
by up to 40%. DSX MaxLPS lets operators
safely deploy more GPUs inside the same power
budget, adding billions in annual revenue.
Breakthrough hot liquid cooling
at 45 degrees Celsius uses less
water and energy — more power going to
revenue-generating compute. Incredible.
Dynamic power allocation steers power from
rack to rack, recovering stranded watts,
sending them where work is happening. In-rack
power smoothing flattens peak current spikes
and power surges. Throughout the factory,
teams of AI agents work with DSX MaxLPS,
continuously coordinating to balance
cooling and power to meet workload demand.
DSX AI factories are flexible energy assets
that operate cooperatively with the grid. DSX
Flex reads real-time grid signals and dynamically
adjusts back to power when the grid needs relief.
100 gigawatts of AI factories will come online
before the end of the decade. NVIDIA DSX AI
factories run at highest efficiency, produce the
lowest-cost tokens, and make the grid stronger.
________________
[JENSEN]
I’ve shown you ecosystem slides of the past,
where NVIDIA’s computing layers and software
stacks are integrated into other people’s
platforms — third-party platforms and libraries
that serve end markets. That was a computing
ecosystem. This is an AI factory ecosystem.
This is way downstream of all of you. Upstream
of me is all of you, and downstream of us is this
ecosystem. Because NVIDIA, ultimately, is not just
building a GPU, not just building a system — we’re
helping customers build these AI factories, this
AI infrastructure, that is so immensely complex.
Each one of these, at one gigawatt level,
started at $20, $30 billion. It is at $50,
$60 billion, and soon it will be $80, $100
billion per gigawatt. $100 billion into an
AI factory. It must work the first time, and
it must work right away. The cost of capital
is incredible. The complexity is incredible.
So as you see, we used to design a chip inside
a computer. And then we simulated a system inside
a computer. Today, you saw just now — everything
was built in Omniverse. I’ve been working with
Omniverse with all of you for a long time.
This was the dream come true, so that we can
build these gigantic systems — as large as the
world wants to build — inside a digital
framework, inside a digital simulator,
in a digital world, long before we
break ground and put our money to work.
So this is our ecosystem. We call it DSX.
RTX is for our GPU, DGX is for our systems,
and now DSX — basically infrastructure.
Because of the work that we do here,
across this entire stack including our systems
and software, it’s the reason why we can work
with small companies and enable them to be
world-class AI clouds. Every one of these
I’m about to show you are small companies — just
recently. And now CoreWeave is worth $50, $60,
$70 billion, and growing incredibly fast.
Recently we worked with Nebius — and again,
they’re growing incredibly fast. Each one of
these clouds has incredible customers: Cursor,
the software coding company; Black Forest Labs,
image generation; World Labs, world foundation
models; Revolut, the leading financial services AI
company; and Shopify. Here’s another one — Nscale,
and their customers are British Telecom, Google
— Google is using one of our AI clouds. Thinking
Machines, a frontier labs company, very exciting.
Here’s NAVER Cloud in Korea — Bank of Korea,
Hyundai, so many incredible companies. Here’s one
in India — Yotta. Incredible companies. Here’s one
based in Singapore, building in Australia
— Together AI, AI Singapore. And here’s one
in Indonesia. Each one of these companies are
serving regional as well as global customers.
AI is going to run everywhere. Every company
will be powered by it, every region will
build it. Indosat, you’re in Indonesia —
here in Taiwan, GMI. It’s okay to clap.
Incredible, incredible companies, incredible
opportunity, but all of them need several
things. Of course, they need the computing stack
— this entire stack underneath. This is what made
NVIDIA famous. All of our hardware and software
and libraries, our connection into the world’s
ecosystem of third-party developers, makes it
possible for anyone to stand up an AI cloud.
However, the AI cloud is so complex now. This
is the software version, the computer science
version. The money version, the asset version, is
what I showed you earlier — it’s a giant factory.
Having this ability alone is not enough,
which is the reason why NVIDIA has become
an AI infrastructure company. Doing this well
— becoming incredibly good at helping customers
build AI factories and deploying AI factories — is
incredibly important, and the reason for that is
this: compute is revenue now. Compute is profit.
The absence of revenue and profit is loss.
And so it’s really important to realize — this is
an example of AI infrastructure coming online. It
could be coming online quickly, it could take
a while. Its throughput could be high, it could
be low. Its resilience, or reliability, could be
good or bad. And its lifetime of usefulness could
be long or short. Because this represents $50,
$60 — going to $100 billion — this curve matters
greatly, which is the reason why NVIDIA is such
a great partner. Working with us, because of our
fully integrated capability — we didn’t just come
up with a PowerPoint slide. We created the entire
infrastructure. We connected everything together.
We built out billions and billions of it ourselves
to make sure that everything works well.
As a result, our time to first token,
our time to first inference, our time to
training turned on is much faster. Second,
because our throughput per watt — tokens per
watt — is utterly world class. And the reason
for that is because we integrate everything,
we design everything from the ground up,
we simulate the entire system, and we use extreme
co-design. Just like I showed you just now with
the Vera Rubin rack — everything was designed in
order to deliver on this incredible throughput.
If your data center, if your factory, has one
gigawatt, it will not have more — that’s all
the power generation you could have. If you have
one gigawatt of power, then throughput per watt is
revenue. Because every token is profitable. Every
token is revenue. This is the future. Compute is
revenue. Performance per watt is your revenue.
Choosing the wrong architecture just because
the chips are cheaper doesn’t translate. Doesn’t
make sense. You need to make sure of your revenue
per watt. The more you buy, the more you make.
And then third is reliability. If you ever get a
chance to see these data centers,
there are so many moving parts,
millions of cables. The ability for all of
those computers to work harmoniously, reliably,
is extremely hard. We have now been operating
at very large scale for a very long time. That
experience matters. That difference — mean time
between interrupts — is extremely important.
And then lastly, this is very hard: the
lifetime of these systems. The software is
changing all the time. Four years ago — the
time of Hopper — AI had completely changed.
Six years ago — the timeframe of Ampere — AI
had completely changed. We started out talking
about CNNs. Then we talked about Transformers.
Then we talked about mixture of experts. Now
we’re talking about agentic systems. Every single
generation, every single few months, the software
industry is coming up with new technology. If your
architecture is not flexible, if your ecosystem is
not rich, then this curve cannot be long. You
cannot predict how long your system can last.
I can. NVIDIA systems are all over the world.
Software developers start with NVIDIA CUDA.
And by definition, therefore, the life — the
ecosystem, the useful asset — is going to be
much longer. The difference is essentially cost.
You could think of it as revenue, but the other
side of revenue is cost. If the life of the asset
is long, the TCO is low. This is the difference.
This is what it looks like
when compute works this way —
the more you buy, the more you make. Now, all
of you are experiencing this with me, isn’t
that right? All of your demand, your factories
are working so hard, your people are working so
hard all across Taiwan, because everybody wants
to make money. They realize that useful AI is
here. Profitable AI is here. Compute demand
is incredibly high, and compute demand is the
constraint. And so, let’s all work super, super
hard and help the world stand up AI factories
everywhere. This is why it’s so important.
I am so happy. Here I am, standing in front of
you — Vera Rubin is in full production.
Vera Rubin is in full production.
The supply chain we created for Vera Rubin
is twice as large as Grace Blackwell. It’s
incredible. And what used to take two hours to
assemble one Grace Blackwell rack now only takes
five minutes. So not only is the capacity
higher, the throughput is a lot faster,
and we need it all to support the demand.
This ecosystem is extraordinary. Millions
of square feet has been put online to support
Grace Blackwell and preparing now — ramping
up now — Vera Rubin. I want to thank all of you.
Vera Rubin is now in full production. Thank you.
Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
Large language models
generate answers. Now, AI agents can do work. But
processing agentic AI is a whole different kind
of problem. Agents observe, reason, plan,
use tools. They manage massive context,
juggling working memory and long-term memory.
They spin up subagents — specialists on demand.
NVIDIA Vera Rubin is a multi-rack, pod-scale
system built to process agentic AI,
and is now in full production.
The manufacturing, automation,
and orchestration across the supply chain — a
miracle to witness. Our journey started when
we launched the first AI supercomputer, NVIDIA
DGX-1. Over the next decade, we pushed every
chip and system to the limit — from Pascal
and the first Ampere, to Grace Blackwell,
the first rack-scale AI supercomputer. And now,
Vera Rubin — the first multi-rack, pod-scale
supercomputer built for the agentic age.
It starts at TSMC. The seven new chips
that make up Vera Rubin take shape
through hundreds of processing steps.
Three-nanometer process. CoWoS advanced packaging.
HBM4 memory from Micron, SK Hynix, and Samsung.
The Vera Rubin GPU — six trillion transistors
with over 18,000 components on one board.
Vera Rubin NVL72 does the thinking — prompt and
context understanding, reasoning, and planning.
Next, a new modular compute tray — streamlined
with a new PCB midplane. ConnectX-9,
SuperNICs, and BlueField-4 DPUs — all
maintenance-accessible with no cables,
for resiliency and AI factory scaling. 18 compute
trays, nine hot-swappable NVLink switch trays. New
high-efficiency liquid-cooled bus bars carrying
over 5,000 amps — the equivalent of 20 electric
cars at full acceleration. Together, 1.3 million
components form this third-generation MGX rack.
Congratulations to Microsoft for their operational
Vera Rubin NVL72 engineering rack. Congratulations
to Dell and CoreWeave as well for standing
up their Vera Rubin NVL72 engineering racks.
Then, the Vera CPU rack — 256 CPUs in a single
liquid-cooled rack, orchestrating the models,
shuffling memory, launching tools. Foxconn
and Quanta brought the Vera LPX rack to
shape — 256 Groq LPUs across 16 trays, 40
petabytes per second of SRAM bandwidth — for
ultra-low latency. While NVL72 generates
tokens at the highest throughput, the
LPX rack generates them at the lowest latency.
Vera BlueField-4 STX — where AI keeps its memory.
Storage processing accelerated by
BlueField-4, connecting memory,
storage, and in-silicon security.
And NVIDIA Spectrum-X Ethernet Photonics — the
world’s first Ethernet switch with 200-gigabit
co-packaged optics. TSMC’s CoWoS process,
chip-scale packaging, and ultra-high-powered
laser dies on indium phosphide.
Vera Rubin — five connected rack-scale
systems, a supercomputer for AI agents.
150 supply chain partners across Taiwan.
Millions of square feet of factory floor,
hundreds of sites. Chips, packages, systems,
and data centers pushed to the limits of size,
power, and scale. This is what we call extreme
co-design. We did this with Taiwan. Together,
we reinvented computing for the age of
AI. Taiwan was with us at the beginning,
and here today, as we bring Vera Rubin
to the world. Thank you, Taiwan.
________________
[JENSEN]
Ladies and gentlemen, Vera Rubin.
Vera Rubin was not built just to run
AI. Vera Rubin was built to run agents. This is
an agentic system. Imagine the complexity — which
is the reason why the agent architecture is the
last great computer science breakthrough. It has
taken this many years for agents to realize
their potential and become useful. It stands
to reason that the computer that runs it is the
most advanced in the world. This is Vera Rubin.
Let’s take a look. Can we
bring out Vera Rubin, please?
And Janine, do we have the racks, the systems?
It looks heavy. This is Vera Rubin — Vera Rubin
NVL72. This is the LPX rack. At the next GTC,
I’m going to talk to you about a lot more of
this. Today, we have so much to talk to you
about. This is the Vera CPU rack — 256 CPUs,
all liquid-cooled. Let me tell you about Vera
in just a moment. This is the Vera BlueField
storage processing system — and also security
system. And of course, this is our Mellanox
networking — the world’s first CPO. This is Vera
Rubin. Incredible technology all coming together.
Now, when we built Hopper, we built Hopper —
as you know — for pre-training. Pre-training
was the most important application, the
most important workload we were working
on at the time. Then when we worked on Grace
Blackwell, everybody said, “Jensen, you know,
NVIDIA is really good at pre-training. Inference
is so easy.” Do you remember that? People used
to say, “Inference is so easy. We could do that
too.” But as you know, inference equals money,
and the models — MoEs — are so complicated,
and to do it at incredibly high response time,
fast interactivity, and high throughput
at the same time is incredibly hard.
Which is the reason why we created NVL72.
Today, NVIDIA’s token cost is the lowest in
the world — not by 10%, but by multiples,
orders of magnitude. All because we did
extreme co-design. All because we understood
the computing model, the computing pattern
of inference, and we were able to create NVL72.
Now with Vera Rubin, it is beyond inference — it
is now inference in an agentic system. This is
Vera Rubin. No cables, no hoses, no fans. What
used to take — the last time I showed this to you
— cables everywhere, amazing to look at. But now
there’s a PCB in the middle which connects both
sides. What used to take two hours now takes five
minutes. The reliability and the resilience
of Vera Rubin is going to be off the charts.
This is our Vera CPU tray — the most advanced
CPU that has ever been built. I want to show
you that in just a second. And this is our
storage tray — two Vera CPUs, four ConnectX-9,
incredible amounts of storage. This is our new
LPX — the Groq LPX rack, designed for very low
latency inference. The throughput is delivered by
Vera Rubin and extended with NVL72. If you want
to extend that even further, you can add Groq
LPUs. Here we have the Vera Rubin NVLink switch
tray — the switches in the middle — and this is
revolutionary. Because of Vera Rubin, because
of NVL72, and the NVLink switches that we created
and invented. And this is our Ethernet switch for
scale-out. What’s amazing is we introduced these
two systems for Grace Blackwell, and today NVIDIA
is the largest networking company in the world.
I’m so proud of the networking team. This is such
an incredible enabler for everything that we do.
I want to now talk to you about the next major
industry we’re going to be part of.
Thank you, Janine. It’s right here —
I think there are 2,000 people
back there pulling them.
Okay, let’s talk about CPUs. Vera CPUs.
CPUs built for the age of agentic AI.
All of the CPUs until now were created for people.
We were the users, we were the renters. The way
we use CPUs — we live in a world counted by
seconds. The way we rent CPUs in the cloud,
the more CPU cores you have, the more you can
rent. The economics and the use case of the
old CPU are fundamentally different from agents.
Agents are impatient. They don’t live in a world
that is counted in seconds. They live in a world
counted in nanoseconds. When an agent uses a tool,
it wants the response time to be as fast as
possible. When it accesses a database, it has
to come back as soon as possible. Every moment
that the agent is waiting keeps it from going
to the next step, the next step, the next step.
It is vital that we make the CPUs as low-latency
as possible, as interactive as possible.
So we created Vera CPU for the age of AI.
Now inside our system, it’s used in three
different ways. The first way, of course,
is within Vera Rubin. For thinking — and inside
the Vera Rubin rack, there are already two
CPUs. As you know, we are building and selling
millions of Vera Rubins. We have sold millions
of Grace Blackwells. And NVIDIA already is
one of the largest CPU makers in the world.
In the Vera Rubin rack there are two CPUs.
One for orchestrating and managing the GPUs,
managing the KV cache, dealing with all of the
software that runs in the rack. We also have
the Grace BlueField that is used for security
and isolation. The Vera compute is used for
the harness, the orchestration of the AI models,
tool use, accessing the database. And the data
servers are right here — Vera BlueField — the
fastest storage servers the world has ever made.
And the reason why this is so vital is because
agents are accessing memory so incredibly fast.
These systems — the storage server and the
CPUs — are in the critical path of the most
expensive part of the data center. This is
the most expensive for a good reason. The
economics of the AI factory are tokens. And the
tokens are created here. And so, of course, you
want to manufacture and generate as many tokens
as possible. This is where you put all of your
economics, and this has to not be in the way.
And so Vera CPU has great requirements on the
CPU architecture, which is the reason why
we built a brand new architecture from the
ground up. A CPU the world has never seen
before. We call it Vera. This is CPU for
agents. All the CPUs of the past, we built
for humans. This CPU is built for agents.
There are four things to keep in mind —
the four takeaways. The first takeaway
is that the instructions per clock
of Vera has to be incredibly good,
because we need the latency to be short. We need
the processing time — single-threaded performance,
not throughput — single-threaded performance has
to be world class. Absolutely the best. Which is
the reason why the IPC, the instructions
per clock of Vera, is so high. It’s the
highest in the world. 10 instructions fetched,
decoded, and executed per clock. Number one.
Number two, the bandwidth necessary to
move data in and out of the CPU has to
be utterly world class — bandwidth per core.
The third is just bandwidth, period. We’re
moving data — and remember, I said earlier,
agentic systems are fundamentally disaggregated
and distributed. Disaggregated and distributed.
When computing is disaggregated and distributed,
networking becomes the problem. Therefore,
we have to move the data around as fast as
possible — between the CPU cores, between the
CPU and the storage, the CPU and the GPU. The
bandwidth around the system, and inside the
CPU core, has to be utterly world class.
This is the first CPU that’s been built in a
long time that is literally at radical limits,
with a fabric that connects all of the CPU
cores at the speed of light — 3.6 terabytes
per second. No trip boundary crossings, because
all of the CPU cores are talking to each other
with extremely high bandwidth. They’re not rented
core by core. They’re all working together. The
cross-sectional bandwidth of Vera is off the
charts. It’s the first CPU to use PCIe Gen 6.
It is also the first to use LPDDR5 with 1.2
terabytes per second — two to three times the
bandwidth of the highest-performance CPUs in the
market. Three times the bandwidth on the inside.
The bandwidth per core, and the bandwidth
overall, is world class. Now, remember — the
number of CPUs is going to be quite high. And
the reason for that is very simple. We created
CPUs for humans in the past, and humans — there
are only a billion of us. There will be billions
of agents. And these agents are going to be using
the CPUs with very little patience, because the
cost of the GPU that they sit next to is too
high, too valuable, too precious. Therefore,
these CPUs are going to be both performant, but
they also have to be extremely energy-efficient,
so that we can pack as much CPU as we can into the
factory without taking away power from the token
generation, which we know is how we make money.
These four properties — instructions per clock,
or single-threaded performance; bandwidth per
core; the total bandwidth around the chip and
inside the chip; and energy efficiency — define
Vera. It is absolutely world class. When you
compare it to the highest-performance x86, it is
just off the charts. When you compare it in real,
single-threaded performance — real performance
— it’s off the charts. It is incredible to be
able to deliver a 5% improvement on CPUs. It is
incredible to be able to deliver 10%. But this
kind of performance speedup is just unheard
of. This is NVIDIA Vera. What do you think?
Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
Agentic AI changes the role
of the CPU. The CPU is now the conductor, and
the GPU is the orchestra. Traditional CPUs were
built for a different era — maximizing cores per
socket, slicing them up, virtualizing, renting by
the hour. In the age of agents, the CPU is now a
bottleneck to GPU utilization, directly affecting
token throughput, latency, and user experience.
NVIDIA Vera is the CPU built for the agentic
loop — combining NVIDIA’s custom data center
CPU core with a scalable coherency fabric,
for the right balance of performance, cores,
and bandwidth to maximize AI factory health.
At the heart of Vera is the NVIDIA
Olympus core, built for modern data
center workloads — branch-heavy Python runtimes,
tool calls, and sandbox code execution. Each core
is tuned for throughput. A neural branch predictor
evaluating two taken branches per cycle. A 10-wide
decode engine brings in more work each cycle.
A large out-of-order engine keeps instructions
moving. Advanced prefetchers with a novel
graph engine anticipating the next data fetch.
But fast cores only matter when data
arrives correctly and on time. Vera is
the first CPU to use LPDDR5X memory while
correcting multiple errors simultaneously
without compromising bandwidth. Vera
achieves 40% lower peak memory latency
versus x86, keeping cores fed on time through
retrieval, analytics, and sandbox execution.
NVIDIA’s second-generation scalable coherence
fabric unifies all 88 Olympus cores on a
monolithic mesh. Separate dies for memory and
cores are not split across chiplets, enabling 50%
faster core-to-core communication than traditional
CPUs. And memory-coherent NVLink chip-to-chip
connects GPUs directly to the CPU. Beyond GPUs,
NVLink chip-to-chip can scale Vera up to multiple
sockets, enabling massive bandwidth between CPUs.
Vera delivers 1.8 times the agentic sandbox
performance of x86 CPUs. Standalone, Vera
racks run agent sandboxes, tools, code,
and data pipelines. Tightly coupled to Rubin
GPUs, Vera keeps accelerated workloads moving.
NVIDIA Vera BlueField-4 STX — powers context,
memory, and AI storage. Compute, network, storage.
Vera is the CPU for the age of agents.
________________
[JENSEN]
This is going to be our new major
growth driver. The reviews are already coming
out, and it’s pretty good. Pretty good stuff.
Now, remember — Grace and Vera are also the
most highly qualified CPUs in the world of AI,
because every single data center, every
single cloud, every single enterprise,
every company that works with NVIDIA on AI has
already qualified Grace. The entire software
stack has already been optimized for Grace. Every
company will be qualifying Vera. Vera will be the
most optimized agentic CPU in the world, simply
because it’s going to go with Vera Rubin, simply
because we made the big architecture switch.
In fact, during the Grace Blackwell transition,
the biggest risk was going from external CPU
x86 into Grace Blackwell. That transition
was extremely challenging. But we did it with
incredible execution. Now Grace is literally
synonymous with Grace Blackwell. When people say
Blackwell, they say Grace Blackwell, because it is
now utterly everywhere. Every company’s software
stack has been optimized for it. Everybody’s
security stack has been optimized for it. And now
here comes Vera. I’m super excited about that.
Now, look at some of the performance numbers.
Speedups are one thing. It is extremely hard
to speed up SQL. SQL — the most famous
domain-specific language that has ever
been created. Before CUDA, it was SQL. Before
OpenGL, there was SQL. Invented by IBM. Today,
it is the structured database language of
the planet. Everybody uses SQL. This is
SQL running three times faster — not 10% faster,
not 25% faster. Three times faster. Incredible.
The next one is real-time stream processing.
Remember, your AI is going to be not just reading
documents. Your AI is going to be watching
for telemetry — especially inside a factory,
inside a stock exchange. You’re going to
be looking for telemetry continuously.
The burst of data that’s coming in
goes into a CPU. This is Vera CPU
running real-time stream processing for
the New York Stock Exchange. Lynn Martin,
the president of the New York Stock Exchange,
has been so gracious to partner with us.
This system runs all over the world, in real
time — real-time stream processing. Vera CPU:
six times faster. All because of the bandwidth,
the single-threaded instruction execution, the
bandwidth inside between the cores, the bandwidth
outside. Vera is completely revolutionary.
You know, talking about x-factors is something
you do when you’re talking about GPUs. It is
quite rare that somebody talks about x-factors
on real workloads associated with a CPU. So I’m
so proud of the team. You guys did such a great
job. We have an extraordinary roadmap coming.
And what’s really exciting is almost everybody
is supporting Vera. They’re as excited as we
are. This is Vera opening up a brand new
market. Agents is a new workload. We built
CPUs for humans in the past. We need CPUs for
agents, for agentic systems. The properties are
different. Why would the CPU be the same? We
are building millions and millions of Veras.
And to go to market with us — Taiwan’s ODMs and
computer makers, all the OEMs — you can see the
early adopters. The early adopters are the agentic
companies. This is the beginning of a new market,
a market that never existed before. It’s
not going to take away from the old markets,
but this is a new market: CPU for agents. And
this market will surely be larger than the last,
because there will be a lot more agents than there
are people, and the agents are very impatient.
So, NVIDIA Vera CPU. Thank you.
This is the most important slide, really. This
is the takeaway. The takeaway here is that this is
the application pattern — the computing pattern of
the next decade. Agents, harnesses, orchestrating
large language models. Every company will run
it. Every company will be an agent company.
Every company will have agents running inside.
Every company will see that agents need their
own operating system. Every company is asking:
how do we run agents safely? How do we
build agents for our own workloads?
And so, we have the NVIDIA Agent Toolkit
for Enterprise AI. You’ve seen me build
this in plain sight. Almost everything that
NVIDIA does — at every GTC — if you go back
and look at my GTC from five years ago or
10 years ago, you will see today. This,
you’ve seen me talking about for several years,
because we’ve been building for this moment.
There are four things that companies need
in order to build agents as a service,
or to build agents to operate. The first thing you
need is models — of course, large language models,
the smarter the better, the cheaper the better,
the faster the better. The second is you need
a harness to orchestrate the whole thing.
The third — these models want to use tools,
and these tools come with skills. And I
showed you CUDA-X libraries — those are
going to be amazing tools for the agents in the
future. And then lastly, you need a runtime. You
need the operating system that holds it all
together. This is the NVIDIA Agent Toolkit.
It includes models that you can modify —
various world-class open models, and I’ll
show you more. You can run agents from anybody.
You can run Claude Code — an incredible agent.
Codex — incredible agent. You could run it inside
this harness called NVIDIA OpenShell, which is
highly secure for inside the enterprise. The shell
protects the agent, keeps it grounded in security
policies. Privacy is protected, its rights and
privileges are given, its identity is protected.
And so this OpenShell is being adopted all over
the world, and it is open source. You can see so
many companies adopting it — Red Hat, Canonical,
Microsoft — it’s going to be adopted everywhere.
This is the runtime. And this runtime is fully
optimized for the NVIDIA AI platform, which is
everywhere. So you can run OpenShell in any cloud,
on-prem, and even on device. You have tools and
libraries that agents can use. You have models
that you can modify or use as-is. Or you have
agents — OpenClaw, Hermes — another incredible
agentic harness. These agentic harnesses can
now run on-prem or for you anywhere.
So, four things, and this represents the
operating system of the modern enterprise.
Now, how do we use this? One of my favorite
use cases of agents is chip designers. It is the
single most important thing that NVIDIA does. And
so, of course, we have to partner with Cadence to
build a super agent — a chip design super agent.
It is orchestrated by Codex or Claude Code. It
has RTL and architecture diagrams, or schematics,
or specifications as input, and whatever you
need to fix. And together, we created some
super agents that are optimized for the NVIDIA
platform, with Nemotron. Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
Cadence and NVIDIA are partnering to build chip
design agents. Hundreds of thousands of NVIDIA
chips come together to make the AI factories
that power the world’s frontier AI models.
Designing these chips, and the systems they run
in, is one of the hardest engineering challenges.
Trillions of transistors. Three-dimensional
circuits at microscopic scale. Every gate,
every wire, synchronized to picoseconds, must work
in perfect harmony, with no margin for error.
Physical prototypes are too slow and too costly.
So engineers work in the digital realm. Each chip
begins as a set of architectural specifications,
then translated into RTL — the language of chip
design. RTL must be verified in simulation. A
single bug can delay a chip by months. At NVIDIA,
thousands of engineers, billions of compute
hours per year, millions of tests written, run,
and debugged — a cycle that takes teams weeks.
To compress this cycle, Cadence and NVIDIA built
a design verification agent. Codex orchestrates
the process. Cadence Chip Stack launches the
RTL verification loop, powered by Nemotron
and secured by NVIDIA OpenShell. Calling on
expert subagents in RTL generation, test bench
creation, regression testing, and debug. The
system drives itself. The Chip Stack agents run
hundreds of simulations with Cadence Xcelium,
formal verification with JasperGold. Design flaws
revealed. Bugs in the code, fixed. What once took
weeks now takes hours. Verification cycles over
40 times faster. Together, NVIDIA and Cadence are
reinventing chip design with AI agents.
________________
[JENSEN]
From weeks to hours.
From weeks to hours. From weeks to hours.
NVIDIA has thousands of chip designers.
We are going to hire hundreds of thousands
of Cadence super agents to work with us,
so that we can accelerate our company,
so that we can be even more ambitious,
create even more amazing things, run even faster.
You saw earlier that the toolkit — with models,
harness, tools and skills, and runtimes — is
the reason why we’re working with Cadence so
hard to accelerate all of their tools on CUDA,
because the agents are impatient. The agents
want the answer immediately. And so, models,
harnesses, CUDA-accelerated libraries and tools,
and then the runtime. What you saw just
now is all of that coming together.
Now, one of the things that it starts with
is a great model that Cadence could modify
and tune to be expert at the Cadence
workflow, at the Cadence expertise,
so that they could create super agents that are
proprietary to Cadence, with their proprietary
knowledge. They have to start with an excellent
model. We call it Nemotron. It is dedicated to
building open models for the world, so that all
of you, all of us, could create our own agents.
Today, we’re announcing Nemotron 3 Ultra. Our
next open model, and it is smart. The Nemotron
models not only give you the model — we give
you all the data that we use to train the model,
and because we have a coalition of incredible
partners, we work together and contribute data
to each other. Nemotron is trained on one of the
largest suites of long-running reasoning models,
long-running tool task-solving, tool-using
datasets in the world, because of all of our great
partnerships. All of this — from the model, the
training scripts, and the data — made completely
available to you. This is open models at its
best. The best open model system in the world.
Simple goal: so that you can take all of it,
add to it, make it even better, make it yours.
Nemotron 3 Ultra is five times faster. This is the
world’s first model based on a hybrid architecture
of SSM — State Space Models — with a Mixture of
Experts. The architecture is incredibly fast.
We made it fast so that you could think fast. When
you think fast, you can think longer at the same
cost. So five times faster. It is also 30% cheaper
— 30% lower cost to run in total FLOPs and total
inference time — than even the most cost-effective
models in the world. We’re comparing against the
world’s best open models. Frontier smart. Five
times faster, 30% cheaper. Completely open. We’re
completely dedicated to this. This is now Nemotron
3. We’re currently working on Nemotron 4.
So this entire toolkit — from models, harnesses,
tools and skills, and runtimes — is the reason
why every enterprise company in the world has
the ability now to create their own agents,
just like Cadence did with their super agents.
And we’re working with so many companies — Cadence
and CrowdStrike, ServiceNow and Palantir, SAP.
People always said, “Jensen, the agents are going
to disrupt these markets.” I said: completely the
opposite. And you can now see it. Agents are going
to create the largest opportunity ever for my
partners and friends. And we have the NVIDIA Agent
Toolkit for Enterprise AI to help them.
So there you go.
First, Vera Rubin in full production. Two,
Vera CPU — CPU built for a new generation,
for agents. And three, NVIDIA’s
Enterprise AI Toolkit, so that
every enterprise and every enterprise
software company can build agents.
My relationship with you started here.
And many of you, many of my friends and
partners here in Taiwan — your companies
started here. This is, in a lot of ways,
the beginning of the modern computer industry
— 40 years now. And NVIDIA is 33 years old.
The PC industry was already starting to get going
— Windows 1, Windows 2, Apple 1, Apple 2 — and by
the time we came along, Windows 3.1 was the PC.
And as you know, Windows 95 made the PC personal.
It took the PC from enterprises and companies
and made it into a consumer electronics device.
Everybody should have one, and everybody does.
This is the beginning. This computing platform
did several things incredibly smart.
Windows was not just disaggregated,
as you know. Windows was properly abstracted.
It was architected just right — system BIOS,
open chipsets, the operating system with drivers
that could be connected and installed at runtime,
and an abstraction layer with a multimedia
API that opened up the PC to what we all
know today. Each one of these elements was
essential in making the PC so popular.
40 years later, Microsoft and NVIDIA are going
to reinvent the PC. This is going to be the new
PC. Now, tomorrow night I’m going to be with
Satya. We’re going to talk a lot more about
the work that we’re doing together. Microsoft and
NVIDIA — over the last three years, it took this
long to completely reinvent how the PC is going to
work so that we could be ready for this moment.
As I mentioned earlier, the computing pattern
called an agent is going to run in AI clouds.
It’s going to run inside enterprises. It is also
going to run on your PC. What’s going to happen
to that PC when it has an autonomous agent? An
agent that’s helping you, that understands you.
You could talk to it. It could look at you.
You can ask it to refile things, go help you,
do some research. It could do a lot more than
I’ll show you. But the new operating system is,
of course, the old operating system plus large
language models. Large language models in a lot
of ways are the modern version of DirectX. It has,
of course, input and output, understands prompts,
it understands computer vision, it can generate
video, it can generate sound. It is the modern
extension — the intelligence extension —
of the PC. On top of that, the application,
as I mentioned before, is going to be replaced
by an agentic runtime. And that is the modern
application: an agent. Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
It started with a spark. An
idea — to reimagine the PC for the first time in
40 years, for the age of AI. What becomes of our
personal computer in a world of agents? Agents
running natively, connected to models — local
or in the cloud — are personal AIs, sandboxed
for security, running continuously, getting
work done. The chips and the OS must evolve.
Introducing RTX Spark — everything we’ve learned
over 33 years, distilled into one chip. Blackwell
RTX GPU with 6,144 Tensor Cores. One petaflop of
AI performance. A custom 20-core Grace CPU, built
in partnership with MediaTek. Fused by NVLink. 128
gigabytes of unified memory. TSMC 3-nanometer
process. 70 billion transistors. And in close
collaboration with Microsoft — a Windows platform
for agents. We’re reinventing the personal
computer. We’re creating for the age of agents.
This is the dawn of a new personal computing
revolution. And it starts with NVIDIA RTX Spark.
________________
[JENSEN]
Here it is. Of course,
I’ve got to show you the most beautiful
part — which is video games. It’s also
the closest to our heart. This is Forza.
This is 007, by the way — the new 007 game,
I’m looking forward to playing
it. I look a little bit like him.
Ladies and gentlemen, NVIDIA
RTX Spark laptops. Now,
thank you. I have too many things in my pocket.
Okay, all right. This is the most amazing chip the
world has ever built. This is the chip we built
in partnership with MediaTek. I think I saw Rick
earlier. This is a beautiful chip. This is a chip
that, frankly, would take 33 years to build. And
the reason for that is because 100% of NVIDIA
software runs here. If you want to run digital
biology, no problem. If you want to do seismic
processing, no problem. You want astrophysics,
no problem. Everything associated with CUDA — all
the physics, all the biology, all the genomics,
all the AI, all the computer graphics — no
problem. Every single application NVIDIA
has ever created, and every single application
that Windows has ever run. Microsoft and NVIDIA
meticulously optimized everything so that this
computer literally runs everything the world has
ever created. Plus, it now runs agents. It is
an incredible computer. I am so proud of it.
Okay. Now, I want you to keep that in mind
for the next video I’m going to show you.
Just imagine — everything here is going to run
on your PC. Now, that computer could have a
local Nemotron 3 Ultra model, or a Nemotron 3
model, or it could have Claude Code, or Codex,
or some other model in the cloud, or something
on the network. And it’s going to work and do
something amazing. Let’s play it.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
Every house starts as
an idea. Getting from idea to design
takes a myriad of tools, expertise,
and a lot of time. Now, an agent running
locally on RTX Spark can help me design
a house using the tools on my laptop — with an
OpenShell sandbox, running the Hermes harness,
connected to Claude Sonnet in the cloud.
I select the site, share my concept sketches
and mood board of styles to inspire my design.
And the prompt — a text description of the
requirements and the design intent. My agent
goes to work. Using the tools on my laptop,
it opens Rhino and starts modeling the site,
shaping terrain, setbacks, and the building
envelope. Then it proposes building forms,
optimized for cost, comfort, and quality.
With the form defined, my agent generates
the interior layout. Walls, circulation,
rooms begin to take shape. I jump in whenever
I want to adjust, to change. Doors, windows,
and structural elements are placed automatically.
My agent detects its own mistakes and fixes them.
When I approve, the agent exports the model
from Rhino into Blender — materials and object
properties transfer with the design context
intact. I fine-tune the materials, get the look
just right. Then I pick the shots. Blender renders
the house. My agent, using generative AI with the
Flux 2 model, makes them photorealistic. Multiple
viewpoints, lighting conditions. What was once a
complex workflow is now guided and simplified
by my agent working on RTX Spark — designed at
the speed of imagination.
________________
[JENSEN]
The developers are so excited
about this — it’s an incredible computer. All of
the acceleration, all the software capabilities
associated with it, working with every
developer to make it incredible for all of you.
The next one — Adobe. Incredible tool suite, used
by tens of millions of people around the world.
They have re-engineered the architecture,
the core of Adobe Photoshop and Premiere,
and they’ll release it for RTX Spark. It is twice
as fast. It’s already fast — now it’s going to be
twice as fast. And it’s also designed to
be agent-friendly — with its MCP server,
it can now interact with agents on your laptop.
The number of partners that are so excited to
bring RTX Spark to market is just incredible.
This is the first great PC reinvention in 40
years. And I’m just so happy that all of you
and the ecosystem around the world has joined
us. This is basically everybody. Everybody
will support RTX Spark, and we’ll be building
incredibly smart and powerful and beautiful
laptops with all of you. Thank you very much.
But that’s not all. RTX Spark is a reinvention of
the laptop. But in fact, Microsoft and NVIDIA are
reinventing all of PC. And today we’re announcing
a whole new line — three revolutionary Windows
machines, covering desktop, laptop, and
workstation — all 100% Windows compatible,
100% CUDA, 100% NVIDIA AI Tensor Core.
Everything that runs on NVIDIA on all
these different platforms around the world, runs
here. This is the first completely re-engineered,
reinvented line of PCs in 40 years.
Now, what’s really amazing is this. So
this is the RTX Spark laptop. This is the desktop.
This one’s from MSI — Joseph, this one’s yours.
Look how beautiful it is. This agent could run
24/7, meter-free. You can download your agent,
you can run it right here. It’s running all the
time. No meter anxiety. And it’s connected to
your whole house — connected to your laptop,
connected to your display, all the cameras,
your dryer, your water cooler, your water heater,
your everything, whatever you want — your security
system. All connected to this. And this becomes
your personal AI, your personal AI agent.
And it gets smarter and smarter and smarter
over time, because today we have Nemotron 3
Ultra. Tomorrow we have Nemotron 4. Then you
switch to Nemotron 5, then Nemotron 6, and we
just keep getting smarter, smarter, smarter. And
meanwhile, this is sitting at home, helping you do
things. If you want to book travel, no problem.
And if you want an incredible system — this is DGX
Station. Compatible with Windows, runs everything
in Windows, and it has 768 gigabytes of memory.
And so you could run a trillion-parameter
model. This is unbelievable. 20 petaflops,
eight terabytes per second of memory
bandwidth, and this sits by your desk.
If you’re a developer of large language models,
a developer of agents — having this sit by your
desk gives you all the compute you need, and then
when you deploy it, you put it in the cloud.
Now, there’s something that, if you look at this
and think about this, something is happening here.
Remember 15, 20 years ago — we used to have
an idea called a phone. Today, when you think
about your phone, the one thing you don’t do
with it is make phone calls. You do just about
everything else. And so that phone means something
very different to you than a phone of the past.
I am certain what’s going to happen here is
that the PC, 10 years from now — the PC that
you think about today, a tool where you launch
applications, click and type — is going to be
completely different. Here’s my theory. I can
totally imagine, just as every house today
has a home theater, big TVs, lawn mowers,
dishwashers — I could totally imagine that
someday there’s actually an AI supercomputer
in your house. And it’s running all of your
agents. It’s running all of your assistants,
and they’re doing all kinds of things for you
all the time. You want AI agent computers
running in your house. And these, in time,
become a lot more like R2-D2 to you. It becomes
more like C-3PO to you than it feels like a PC.
There is no question — this reinvention of the
computer is as big a deal as the reinvention of
the phone into what we now know as the smartphone.
And so, this is the beginning of that journey.
This is the beginning of a new line. We have a
roadmap for this — a brand new product family.
Every single generation of architecture, we will
have a desktop, a laptop, and a workstation.
And the thing that I’m just incredibly pleased
and incredibly honored by is that 100% of the
world’s PC industry has joined us to reinvent
the PC. A new line, a new beginning. Thank you.
As you know, agentic AI is just a digital
robot. It understands, it reasons, it plans,
and it acts and uses tools. Agentic AI is going to
run across all of these computers. We’re working
on humanoid robotics computers, robotics computers
of all kinds. We’re working on self-driving car
computers. We’re working on satellites. You
have GeForce, which has Tensor Cores. I just
talked about a whole new line of PCs. Agriculture
equipment, manufacturing equipment, heavy industry
equipment — all will be agentic. Even your base
stations — the radio stations of the future — are
going to be agentic, understanding traffic and
thinking about how to coordinate with other base
stations so that you can use as little energy as
possible, increasing the spectral efficiency.
And so everything will run agents. Today, NVIDIA
is largely in the center. But I am pretty certain
that there will be tens of billions, hundreds of
billions over time, of agentic systems and agentic
computers running around the world.
The biggest problem is data. In the
case of language models, all the English and
all the language that we have on the internet
that we train on was from the perspective
of us — we wrote it and we’re reading it.
However, in order to create data for AI robotics,
it has to be from the perspective of the robot.
And most of the world’s video data is from
a third person, not first person. And so,
agentic systems, robotic systems, physical
AI — the data is the hardest problem.
You’ve seen us move up this ladder. We started
with teleoperation, which is basically human
demonstration — no different than the big
breakthrough of reinforcement learning from human
feedback. Then we use simulation — this is
where Omniverse comes in, no different than
reinforcement learning with verifiable rewards.
We use these systems to bootstrap the AI model,
the physical AI model. Eventually we’re able
to learn from third-person data, reprojecting
into first person. And now, eventually, through
bootstrapping, we have a World Foundation Model
that can understand the physical world from any
perspective you want — third person, first person,
inside and out. This is a big breakthrough.
And today, we’re announcing Cosmos 3.
Cosmos 3 is the frontier of physical AI. We are at
the frontier with language models — there are so
many people working on it. However, in physical
AI, we are absolutely the world’s best. I am so
proud of the team for doing this. This is the
Foundation Model for all of your work. Whenever
you want to create a robot — a factory robot, a
robot that works in a factory, any kind of robot
that involves the physical world — you now have
a companion in Cosmos 3 that can understand and
reason. It can generate, it can simulate, and in
the loop it can even be the policy itself. It is
at the top of leaderboards all over the world.
I am incredibly proud of Cosmos, and today we’re
announcing Cosmos 3. Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
The real world is infinite
and unpredictable. Physical AI needs data,
but real-world data is impossible to scale.
For physical AI, compute is data. This is Cosmos
— an open frontier omni-model for physical AI,
built on a new Mixture of Transformers
architecture. Pixels, action, sound,
and language flow into the
autoregressive transformer,
which reasons, plans, and instructs the diffusion
transformer, which generates what comes next.
Developers post-train Cosmos across
embodiments and use cases. As a VLM,
Cosmos watches the physical world, understands
what’s happening, describing scenes and flagging
what matters. As a world model, Cosmos generates
physics-accurate synthetic video from an image,
text, or video. As a simulator, Cosmos closes
the loop for policy training and evaluation.
And as the foundation of NVIDIA OmniDreams
— an action-conditioned world model — Cosmos
predicts the future frame by frame.
Post-train Cosmos and it becomes a world
action model — perceiving, reasoning, planning,
generating actions — for robots of every kind,
for everything that moves. A new
kind of data. A new kind of teacher,
generated by compute. Cosmos — the foundation
for developers in the age of physical AI.
________________
[JENSEN]
Text data plus compute gives you AI. Now that we
have AI, compute is data. And so, use Cosmos 3,
train a whole bunch of models. Cosmos is such
an incredible open model system — it’s exactly
the same as Nemotron. We open the model, we open
the data, and we even open how we trained it so
that you can enhance it for yourself and
turn Cosmos into your proprietary model.
We have such incredible partners working
with us in so many different industries.
Now, the model itself is, of course, the most
understandable part of the AI stack. But the AI
stack is very complicated — it has generators, the
model, simulators, and the runtime. Just as it is
for agentic systems, cars are essentially physical
AI — agentic robots that are autonomous vehicles
— and they have this complicated stack too.
Today we’re announcing Alpamayo 2 Super, an
open model for self-driving cars. We’re
working with car companies across the world.
If you look at the brands that have signed up
for NVIDIA DRIVE Hyperion — that are building
NVIDIA DRIVE Hyperion cars — this represents
about 80% of the world’s car manufacturers.
We are going to have a whole lot of NVIDIA
DRIVE Hyperion systems that are able to run
Alpamayo 2 Super, or anybody else’s NVIDIA
stack. We are also connected into mobility
services — approximately 97% of the world’s
mobility services are connecting with us — so
that when we deploy Alpamayo 2 Super on the DRIVE
Hyperion runtime, with the Halos operating system,
we will be able to connect to all of these
services across the world. Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
Hey Mercedes, let’s go to
my favorite sandwich shop.
Routing to your destination. Lane is clear,
pulling out to start drive. Nudge left due
to the stationary lead vehicle ahead blocking
our lane. Slow down to stop at the stop sign,
controlling the intersection. Stop to yield to
the pedestrians. Since the person is in our lane,
yield for the cutting vehicle from the left. Nudge
left to clear the stopped vehicle blocking on the
right. Keep distance to the cutting vehicle
since it is merging into our lane. There is a
lane stream crossing ahead. Stop to keep distance,
decelerate. Stop at the stop sign, intersection is
controlled. Stop, yield to the cross traffic. Keep
distance to the truck. Nudge left due to the truck
blocking on the left side of our lane.
Your destination is on the right.
Alpamayo 2 Super — the world’s first reasoning
autonomous vehicle.
________________
[JENSEN]
If you let it talk all the time, it will drive
you crazy. But we’re very happy that it’s talking
to itself all the time. That’s called thinking.
And so Alpamayo 2 Super is a reasoning car.
The technology that we’ve created also applies
to humanoids. Of course, there are many
new breakthroughs that have to happen.
NVIDIA Isaac GR00T is our humanoid robotics
stack — model, data generation, simulation,
the runtime including the operating system.
This represents the GR00T platform, the Isaac
GR00T platform. Every one of our systems — the
exact same architecture — whether it’s an agentic
system for the cloud, an agentic system for the
PC, a robotic system for a self-driving car,
a robotic system for a humanoid robot — all
the same. And of course, in every single case,
we build everything completely. We built
everything vertically, completely integrated
with co-design, extreme co-design. And
then when we open it up for everybody
to use — whichever part you like, whatever
you want to use, we even help you modify.
But the one thing that is missing is we need
a reference platform for robotic systems.
These robotic systems are so complicated
— so many motors, so many sensors,
so fragile — and yet we need to have a way to
deliver these reference platforms, just like we
do with PCs and DGXs and clouds and self-driving
cars. We now are going to do it for robots. Today,
we’re announcing the NVIDIA Isaac GR00T reference
humanoid robot — fully integrated. 25 degrees of
freedom on each hand, made by Sharpa. 31 degrees
of freedom on the robot, 6 feet, 150 pounds. Just
like me. The first number is shorter, the second
number is bigger. Otherwise, pretty close.
And this platform runs the new Jetson Thor and
our entire software stack — data generation stack,
data simulation stack, the runtime —
all integrated into a robot designed
for everyone to use. We built this for
higher education and university researchers,
because for them to build this themselves is
insanely hard. And so let’s take a look at that.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
The next leap in AI is general-purpose
robots — humanoids. But building one is
hard. Every team starts from scratch, stitching
together simulators, teleoperation systems,
data pipelines, and training infrastructure.
Months of setup before research can start.
NVIDIA Isaac GR00T — an open development
platform for humanoid robots. Open models,
simulation and training libraries, and data
generators. Plus, the robot computer — fully
pre-configured, ready to go in hours.
First, set up the simulation environment
in Isaac Lab. Capture demonstrations with
Isaac Teleoperation on a real or simulated
robot. Generate synthetic data with Omniverse and
Cosmos, scaling one demonstration into thousands.
Train policies, evaluate them in Isaac Lab Arena.
Deploy through Isaac ROS, running on Jetson Thor.
Every element is modular and open — use ours
or swap in your own. GR00T is powering robotics
research across every discipline for every
domain, from research labs to factory floors.
One open platform. And now, a new edition: Isaac
GR00T reference design robots — built on NVIDIA’s
open platform, ready for frontier research, for
any lab, anywhere. The age of robotics starts
here. NVIDIA Isaac GR00T.
________________
[JENSEN]
So many robots. Well, we can just
let everybody who’s working on robots in the world
— let me tell you what I told you. The computer
industry has been completely changed. In the
last six months, everything changed. Everything
changed because agents were realized, and it
converged with the latest frontier models, and
it made possible for AI to now do useful work.
The computing pattern will repeat over and over
and over again. This computing pattern — an agent
that has a model, a harness that uses tools with
skills, and runs in a runtime — that runtime
depends on whether it’s in a cloud or on-prem,
on a PC or a robot. But the computing pattern
is exactly the same for all of them. You will
use different harnesses because of your
preference. You’ll use different models
because of your preference. You will improve
them for your proprietary use. You would
create super agents that you can offer to
other people to help them do their work.
This agentic platform, this agentic pattern —
NVIDIA has an Enterprise AI Toolkit. This is a
wonderful way for all of you to engage with AI,
and for us it’s a wonderful growth opportunity.
Vera Rubin is in full production. Whereas Grace
Blackwell was created to process AI — particularly
inference — Vera Rubin was created to run agents.
It is in full production. It is much, much more
than a GPU. It is an entire, disaggregated,
distributed agent processing system.
NVIDIA has really become an infrastructure company
— not just a GPU company, not just a systems
company, but an infrastructure company to help you
generate the maximum revenue, the maximum profit,
and to get there as soon as possible.
The agentic world — this new way of
computing — where you build CPUs for agents,
not for people. CPUs for agents have their
own special requirements, and NVIDIA Vera is
revolutionary. I’m so happy about its ramp.
The orders are already in. It’s going
to be the fastest and most successful
product launch in our company’s history.
NVIDIA and Microsoft have created a whole
new line of PCs. This is a new beginning, and of
course, the exact same agentic computing pattern
that I just described is also going to run on
all kinds of devices. I mentioned PCs, but in
the future it’ll be robots and satellites and base
stations and factories — in the cloud, on-prem,
at the edge. This agentic computing pattern will
be replicated in computers all over the world.
How we think about the personal computer will very
likely change. I want to thank all of you for your
partnership, your friendship. We couldn’t be here
without everything that we do together. I am so
proud of how successful you’ve been this last
year. The next year is going to be even more. I
have one more thing for you. Let’s take a look.
________________
[VIDEO NARRATION]
[Closing performance — partial lyrics as
captured:]
Useful AI has arrived,
agents working by your side. Can’t miss the
things we said today — we’re gonna break it
all down for you, Taipei. Agents — widely
misunderstood, only movie stars had them
in Hollywood. Now they’re your coworkers, making
dreams come true, building companies from living
rooms. There’s so much confusion — we hear you.
That’s why we created Vera, gonna show it’s true.
The cheapest token coming through. Ten times
throughput — more for special agents, double
down. Vera keeps agent memory true. Now let’s talk
about it — CPU. Fifty percent faster. Not for x86.
It’s built for agents. Everyone’s welcome to the
NVIDIA party. Vera Rubin in full production. 5X,
faster work is done. OpenShell, keep the sandbox
tight. Here’s a five-layer cake, make no mistake.
MaxLPS keeps power lean. Optimized for you —
so you can have your cake and eat it too. PC
reinvention — 40 years. Running anywhere Windows
goes. Turning compute into synthetic data,
reasoning through, understanding the world
like people do. It’s how they learn to move.
The future’s here — come see what’s next.
________________
[JENSEN]
Thank you, Taiwan. Welcome to Computex.
Have a great time, everyone.
Thanks for an amazing year.
Thank you for all your friendship
and support. Thank you. Take care.